Let's look at how self-attention works in a little bit more detail.
我们详细了解下自注意力的原理
Let's say, we have these words that we want
假设我们希望编码器阅读这些单词
our encoder to read and create a representation of.
并创建表示结果
As always, we begin by embedding them into vectors.
和之前一样 首先将它们嵌入为向量
Since the transformer gives us a lot of flexibility for parallelization,
因为 Transformer 使我们能够非常灵活地并行处理
this example assumes we're looking at the process or
这个示例假设进程或 GPU
GPU tasked with encoding the second word of the input sequence.
对输入序列的第二个单词进行编码
First step is to compare them.
第一步是比较它们
So, we score the embeddings against each other.
我们通过相互比较对嵌入评分
So, we have a score here and a score here,
这是一个得分 这是一个得分
comparing this word that we're currently reading or
将当前正在阅读或编码的这个单词
encoding with the other words in the input sequence.
与输入序列中的其他单词进行比较
We scale the score.
对得分进行缩放
We basically divide by two here.
这里是除以 2
The dimension of the keys,
即键的大小
which we're using a toy dimension of four,
这里使用的是示例维度 4
so that would be two.
因此这里是 2
We do a softmax for these, and then,
对它们应用 softmax
we multiply the softmax score with
然后将 softmax 得分与嵌入相乘
the embedding to get the level of expression of each of these vectors.
获得每个向量的表达级别
The embedding of the current word, just [inaudible] as it is.
当前单词的嵌入直接按原样传入
We add them up, and that produces the self-attention context vector,
相加 生成自注意力语境向量
if that's something we'd like to call it.
如果要取个名称的话
This is the image the authors of the paper showed when they
当该论文的作者第一次在 NIPS 大会上
presented this paper first at the NIPS Conference.
公布这篇论文时 他们展现了这个图像
Then, we're looking at the second word.
然后 我们查看第二个单词
So, we have the words here, and then,
这些是单词
they have their embeddings, and then,
这些是嵌入
these are the vectors of the embeddings.
这些是嵌入向量
So, this word is compared or scored against each of the other words in the input vector.
将这个单词与输入向量中的每个其他单词进行比较或对其评分
This score is then multiplied by the embedding of that relevant word,
然后将这个得分与该相关单词的嵌入相乘
and then, all of these are added up.
将所有这些结果相加
We did not score the current word.
我们没有对当前单词评分
We scored all the other words.
而是对所有其他单词评分
After we add them up, we just pass this up to the feedforward neural network.
将它们相加后 将这个传入前馈神经网络
If we implement it like this, however,
但是 如果这么实施的话
we could see that the model is mainly focusing on other similar words,
可以看出 如果仅根据单词嵌入判断
if we judge it only on the embedding of the word.
模型主要侧重于其他相似单词
So, there's a little modification that we need to do here.
因此这里需要做个小小的修改
We need to create queries out of each embedding.
我们需要通过每个嵌入创建查询
We do that by just multiplying by a query matrix or just
为此 我们乘以查询矩阵
passing it through a query feedforward neural network.
或将其传入查询前馈神经网络
We also create keys.
此外还创建键
So, we have another separate matrix of keys.
这是另一个单独的键矩阵
We can calculate that again.
再计算一遍
So, we have our embeddings,
这是嵌入
we create the queries.
创建查询
We're only processing the second word here.
这里仅处理第二个单词
So, that's where we created the query for.
因此仅为这个单词创建查询
Then, we have our keys here.
然后 这里是键
The scoring is comparing the query versus the key.
评分函数将查询与键进行比较
So, that's where we get these numbers here,
获得这些数字
40, and then, 26.
40 和 26
We scale softmax, and then,
进行缩放 应用 softmax
we multiply the softmax score with the key.
然后将 softmax 得分与键相乘
That gets us the self-attention context vector after we add all of these together.
将所有这些相加后 得出自注意力语境向量
This is an acceptable way of doing it,
这是可接受的方式
but there is a variation that we need to look at as well.
但是还需要查看另一种版本
So, these are our embeddings.
这是嵌入
We have our queries,
这是查询
which are made by multiplying the embedding by the Q matrix,
通过将嵌入与 Q 矩阵相乘得出查询
which is learned from the training process.
Q 矩阵是在训练流程中学习到的矩阵
We have our keys, which are created by multiplying the embeddings by the K matrix,
这是键 通过将嵌入与 K 矩阵相乘得出键
and we have our values,
这些是值
which are produced the same way by multiplying by the V matrix,
生成方法一样 将嵌入与 v 矩阵相乘
which is also learned in the training process.
v 矩阵也是在训练流程中学到的矩阵
This is a graphic from the authors as well in their NIPS presentation,
这是作者在论文中及他们的 NIPS 演讲中提供的图形
where they outline how to create the key,
他们概述了如何创建键
the query, and the value.
查询和值
So, this is the embedding.
这是嵌入
We multiply it by V to get the value.
将其与 v 相乘得出值
We multiply it by Q to get the query.
与 q 相乘得出查询
You multiply it by K to get the key.
与 k 相乘得出键
So, the final form of self-attention,
就像这篇论文中呈现的一样
as presented in this paper,
自注意力的最终形式
is, we have our embeddings.
包括嵌入
We've calculated our V,
计算出 V Q
Q, our values, keys, and queries.
值 键和查询
We score the queries against the keys,
通过与键对比对查询评分
and then, that softmax score is multiplied by the values.
然后将 softmax 得分与值相乘
These we add up and pass to the feedforward neural network.
将这些相加 传递给前馈神经网络
This is a very high-level view at this model here
这是这个模型的简单概览
and discussion of the self-attention concept.
并讨论了自注意力概念
In the text below the video,
在视频下方的文本中
we'll link to the paper and some implementations of it,
我们提供了该论文和一些实现的链接
if you're interested to go a little bit deeper into the transformer.
帮助你深入了解 Transformer